Adolf Seilacher Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Adolf Seilacher Archives
1967-2006
IPAR.001114
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
5
The archives of Adolf Seilacher including maps, field notes, lecture material etc. encompassing his time at Yale.
Seilacher, Adolf
Biographical Sketch
Born in 1925, Professor Adolf Seilacher studied in Tubingen under Otto H. Schindewolf. He has taught in Frankfurt, Baghdad, Gottingen, Baltimore, and Tubingen, and has been Adjunct Professor at Yale University since 1987. In 1992, the Swedish Academy of Science awarded him the Crafoord Prize, established for fields not covered by the Nobel Prize. Professor Seilacher, perhaps the world's most acknowledged expert in the field of trace fossils, is also known for his contributions to morphology and structuralism, biostratinomy, exceptional preservation and Ediacaran biota.
Description of the Material
Includes field notes and locality information about Libya, China, India, Canada (Ontario and Newfoundland), USA (Maine, New York, North Carolina), Colombia, and Argentina. Also includes correspondence from 1990-2003.
Connecticut; New York; Canada; Germany; USA; Maps; Drawings; Field notebooks; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Field Notes, 2004-2006; Series I
  - 2004., 001119
    - Field notes. field notebook, Libya, etc (Notebook 2004-2), 000903
  - 2006., 001120
- Maps, Series II
  Scope and Contents
  Topographic maps.
  - New York., 001121
    - Topographic map. Sarqatoga Springs, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000).;This map was given to Paleobotany Division March 10, 2003 U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1967; 002102
  - Newfoundland., 001122
    - Topographic map. Trepassey, Newfoundland: 1 K/11 (1: 50000). Surveys and Mapping Branch, Department of Energy, Mines and Resources, Canada: Topographic., 1985; 001930
- Specimen Information, Series III
  - Catalog of Identifications., 001123
    - Catalog of identifications. Catalog of trace fossil casts: Europe; North America., 1987; 000005
    - list of 73 lots of plaster casts of ichnofossils (tract fossils) prepared by Robert Allen; Most originals are in Tubingen, Germany, 2004; 000790
  - Photographs & Illustrations., 001124
    - Photographs & Negatives. Two black and white negatives of limpet nests and shell including YPM 36020, 36023. Black and white negatives, 1996; 000581
    - information on & drawings of specimens to be published in his new book & other pubs., 1994; 000481
    - Original drawings and xeroxes of original drawings showing YPM numbers. Many of these images were used in the 2014 Morphodynamics book., 002710
- Miscellaneous, Series IV
  Miscellaneous archives associated with Adolf Seilacher including locality information. lecture material and correspondence.
  - Correspondence., 1990-2003; 001127
    - Papers, notes, correspondence. Correspondence of Adolf Seilacher, 1990-2003, 000932
  - Lecture Material., 001126
    - Manuscript material. locality and faunal information and manuscript; Bogota, Colombia., 1927; 000382
    - 35 MM slides of Permian Akaska limestone slab from Japan. Broken during Seilacher's class project 12/1993 35 mm slides, 000573
    - Overhead transparencies (8.5 x 11 in) used by Dolf Seilacher in his lectures between 1987 and 2009 at Yale, 000933
  - Locality Information., 001125
    - Locality information. Locality information, Precambrian of North Carolina, & Cambrian of Newfoundland, Argentina, Maine. 1989, 1991, 000707
    - Locality information. Notes and papers of Vendozoa collections from Mistaken Point: Newfoundland., 1990; 000336
    - Locality information. Photocopy of Romulus 7.5 Quad with Seneca Stone Quarry locality: & Finger Lakes Stone quarry, Ithaca; New York: all Oct, 2007 field trip. 1990, 1991; 2007, 000353
    - Locality information. Locality information and student article; Chengjiang and Kaili faunas, Cambrian of China; and 35 mm color slides (photographs), 1995; 000799
    - Locality information. Locality information for Precambrian Triploblast, Chorhat, India, 1997; 000803
    - Locality information. Locality information, Ontario, Canada; Potsdam Grp., 2000; 000738
  - Miscellaneous., 002711
    - Announcement from the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences about Dolf Seilacher winning the Crafoord Prize in 1992, 002721
    - Miscellaneous "Dolfiana" including his lifetime bibliography., 002712
    - original drawings, unpublished manuscripts, original material for published manuscripts, reprints of others, meetings, taxonomic groups, photos of Dolf and others., 002725